[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "She insisted on leaving the house.",
    "options": ["he", "him", "himself", "His"],
    "answer": "His"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The phrase 'Achilles' heel' means-",
    "options": [
      "a strong point",
      "a strong solution",
      "a weak point",
      "a permanent solution"
    ],
    "answer": "a weak point"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "He does not adhere __ any principle.",
    "options": ["by", "in", "at", "to"],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Millennium is a period of-",
    "options": ["100 year", "1000 year", "1 million year", "1 billion year"],
    "answer": "1000 year"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Identify the passive form of the following sentence: 'Who has broken this jug?'",
    "options": [
      "By whom has this jag been broken?",
      "By whom has this jug broken?",
      "By whom this jug has been broken",
      "Whom has this jug been broken?"
    ],
    "answer": "By whom has this jag been broken?"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Who is not a Victorian poet?",
    "options": [
      "Alfred Tennyson",
      "Robert Browning",
      "William Wandsworth",
      "Matthew Arnold"
    ],
    "answer": "William Wandsworth"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following novels was written by George Orwell?",
    "options": [
      "1984",
      "Brave New World",
      "A Clockwork Orange",
      "For Whom the Bell Tolls"
    ],
    "answer": "1984"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Identify the correct sentence:",
    "options": [
      "She speaks English like English",
      "She speaks the English like English.",
      "She speaks the English like the English",
      "She speaks English like the English"
    ],
    "answer": "She speaks English like the English"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "When one makes a promise, one must not go __ on it.",
    "options": ["forward", "by", "back", "around"],
    "answer": "back"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "I can't put up with him any more. Here 'put up with' means:",
    "options": ["To protect", "To terminate", "To tolerate", "To prevent"],
    "answer": "To tolerate"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "The poem 'To His Coy Mistress' was written by:",
    "options": [
      "Andrew Marvell",
      "John Donne",
      "George Herbert",
      "Henry Vaughan"
    ],
    "answer": "Andrew Marvell"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "The synonym of 'altitude' is-",
    "options": ["height", "width", "length", "depth"],
    "answer": "height"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The character, Elizabeth Bennett, appears in the novel-",
    "options": [
      "Pride and Prejudice",
      "Tess of the d'Urbervilles",
      "Wuthering Heights",
      "Jane Eyre"
    ],
    "answer": "Pride and Prejudice"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "This could have worked if I - been more far-sighted.",
    "options": ["have", "had", "might", "would"],
    "answer": "had"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What may be considered courteous in one culture may be arrogant in another. Here the word 'arrogant' means-",
    "options": ["rude", "gracious", "coarse", "pretentious"],
    "answer": "rude"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Don Juan was composed by-",
    "options": [
      "WB Yeats",
      "E. B. Browning",
      "George Gordon Byron",
      "Alexander Pope"
    ],
    "answer": "George Gordon Byron"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Identify the imperative sentence:",
    "options": [
      "Shut up!",
      "Shahin is playing football.",
      "I shall cook dinner now.",
      "What is your name?"
    ],
    "answer": "Shut up!"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "'Black Death' is the name of a --",
    "options": [
      "fever",
      "black fever",
      "plague pandemic",
      "death of black people"
    ],
    "answer": "plague pandemic"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "'Ulysses' is a poem written by-",
    "options": [
      "Robert Browning",
      "Wordsworth",
      "S.T. Coleridge",
      "Alfred Tennyson"
    ],
    "answer": "Alfred Tennyson"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Who wrote the poem 'Ozymandias'?",
    "options": [
      "Thomas Hardy",
      "Robert Frost",
      "P. B. Shelley",
      "Edmund Spenser"
    ],
    "answer": "P. B. Shelley"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Clym Yeobright is the protagonist of the novel-",
    "options": [
      "David Copperfield",
      "Adam Bede",
      "A Passage to India",
      "The Return of the Native"
    ],
    "answer": "The Return of the Native"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "The train is running - forty miles an hour.",
    "options": ["on", "to", "at", "for"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "He divided the money - the two children.",
    "options": ["between", "over", "among", "in between"],
    "answer": "between"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "No one can --- that he is clever.",
    "options": ["defy", "deny", "admire", "denounce"],
    "answer": "deny"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Choose the right form of verb: The boy (to lie) on the floor yesterday.",
    "options": ["lies", "lied", "lay", "layed"],
    "answer": "lay"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "She played on the flute. Passive form is-",
    "options": [
      "The flute was played by her.",
      "The flute was played on by her.",
      "The flute was being played by her.",
      "The flute was played to her."
    ],
    "answer": "The flute was played on by her."
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Antonym for ‘Adieu’-",
    "options": ["Farewell", "Good bye", "Hello", "Valediction"],
    "answer": "Hello"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "'Walk fast lest you should miss the train'. This is a-",
    "options": [
      "Simple sentence",
      "Compound sentence",
      "Complex sentence",
      "Integrative sentence"
    ],
    "answer": "Complex sentence"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "A number of singers in a church is called-",
    "options": ["Choir", "Cast", "Claque", "Clump"],
    "answer": "Choir"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Put the right word in the blank. He reached the - of his literary career.",
    "options": ["abattoir", "acme", "admonish", "abdicate"],
    "answer": "acme"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Anger may be compared - fire.",
    "options": ["to", "within", "against", "Into"],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Choose the correct sentence:",
    "options": [
      "He discussed the matter.",
      "He discussed about the matter.",
      "He discussed on the matter.",
      "None of the above."
    ],
    "answer": "He discussed the matter."
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Identify the correctly spelt word.",
    "options": ["Horroscope", "Pneumonia", "Occassion", "Embarass"],
    "answer": "Pneumonia"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Desdemona is a character in the following Shakespearean play:",
    "options": ["Macbeth", "Othello", "Hamlet", "King Lear"],
    "answer": "Othello"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Meteorology is related to-",
    "options": [
      "concrete slabs",
      "motor vehicles",
      "weather forecasting",
      "motor neuron disease"
    ],
    "answer": "weather forecasting"
  }
]
